Wayne Knerr

Engineer - Microsoft via Insight Global

Redmond, WA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Wayne-Knerr/ff1942585e51d187

Brings over 10 years of quality assurance experience. Specialties include development and execution of automated & manual testing, application testing, requirement reviews, test case creation and detailed defect reports analysis. Performs seamlessly within the given test environment. Extensive background delivering results as a Software Engineer. Demonstrates proven experience contributing to a company's overall growth and performance. Most recent work at Microsoft encompassed testing Azure Cloud Storage and Data Deduplication.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Microsoft via Insight Global - Redmond, WA - February 2016 to Present

Software development and testing for the Azure Storage team.

Software development, testing and Hardware Support for the Data Deduplication team.

- Microsoft Azure Storage team:
- Create scripts to run performance, stress / longhaul, generate reports.
- Create churn scripts to simulate user modification of data.
- Optimize performance of Azure storage endpoints.
- Create testbed and execute testing for Azure performance.
- Microsoft Data Deduplication team:
- Create scripts for stress / longhaul, performance testing.
- Create and perform testing of Nebula, Hyper-V virtual machines and physical machines.
- Setup and configure Servers and VMHosts as needed.
- Manage hardware.

Software Test Engineer

Spacelabs Healthcare via Terra Staffing Group - Snoqualmie, WA - January 2015 to June 2015

Software Test Engineer on the ICS team:

- Tested cutting-edge software for critical care monitoring equipment.
- Utilized TFS to manage defects
- Used SQL queries to verify data.
- Reviewed requirements and wrote test cases as needed.

Quality Assurance Tech on the AWS Marketing team

Amazon via Insight Global - Seattle, WA - August 2013 to December 2013

Tested the migration of a large scale marketing site: aws.amazon.com

- Created test cases
- Performed various manual testing such as page rendering, functional and sanity for Mac OS X cross-browser & mobile devices
- Took notes while running test pass in order to go back and perform in-depth exploratory testing in areas of concern
- · Executed automated testing using Eclipse, Jmeter and Selenium

- Utilized Firebug and other native web tools to debug script errors
- · Filed, prioritized and assigned bugs via Jira

Sr. Quality Assurance Analyst

Razorfish via Robert Half Technology - Seattle, WA - May 2012 to December 2012

Sr. Quality Assurance Analyst on the Delivery Management team:

- Tested small, medium and large scale web sites and apps
- Participated in daily stand-ups and work within short sprints
- · Created test cases and delivered to customer
- Tested bing.com allnew.msn.com and integration of our HTML5 video player
- Tested retail demo app on various systems such as Microsoft Surface by altering values in the Win8 app control panel and verify by directly editing the XML file
- Tested three tiers of localization for the Windows 8 Retail Demo Experience on the about.me web app
- Generated and modified localized test content for testing on the backend via CMS tools such as Sitecore, Ektron and Microsoft Harmony
- Tested on various mobile devices such as iPhone, iPad, Android, Windows and Blackberry using emulators when necessary

Software Test Engineer III

Microsoft via VMC - Redmond, WA - November 2010 to January 2012

Software Test Engineer III on the Security Devices team:

- Ensured test coverage of our Smart-card readers, Biometric devices and Smart cards
- Created driver repository to automate third party driver and application installs
- Reduced the time the tester spent preparing the test environment by automating the installation and configuration process
- Performed a combination of manual and automated testing, ensuring the compatibility of the Security Device Drivers and Fingerprint Management Applications
- Driver coverage sources are Windows in-box, Windows Update, and third party device drivers via the manufacturer's website
- Track multiple device driver sets with version history
- Smoke private driver and application drops
- Compiled detailed test reports and analysis
- Documented all setup, configuration and test procedures and stored on our teams SharePoint wiki to safeguard tribal knowledge

Software Test Engineer III

Microsoft via Compucom - Redmond, WA - January 2009 to December 2009

Software Test Engineer III on the IHV readiness team:

- Tested IHV reference platforms performance and general system stability of alpha BIOS and drivers while running under Windows Vista and Windows 7
- Executed Velocity Performance tests on IHV reference platforms and compared these with the results of all relevant OEM platforms
- Automated and enhanced the test process while suggesting additional testing and clearly documenting created procedures on SharePoint Wiki
- Work with IHV business partners, resolving platform issues upstream enabling discovery on issues before being integrated into an OEM deliverable machine
- · Raised issues during scrum meetings, avoiding future problems
- Provided post-mortem analysis

Software Test Engineer III

Microsoft via Compucom - Redmond, WA - May 2008 to December 2008

Software Test Engineer III on the OEM engagement team:

- Utilized WTT, ASI, cmdline and other scripts to capture and deploy OEM system images and then configure the environment to prepare them for testing
- Tested driver and application compatibility during the upgrade migration process from Vista to Win 7 on over 100 OEM systems; compared results against factory image and clean installs of Win 7
- Used 'Driver Verifier' and 'PNPDtest' to stress test the drivers on Vista & Win 7; analyzed any resulting kernel debug breaks
- Obtained device driver PNP-ID via device manager and driver inf file
- Worked with team and outside OEM representative's to drive application and device driver issues through to resolution

Lab Engineer

Microsoft via Compucom - Redmond, WA - May 2006 to May 2007

Lab Engineer on the Internet Explorer Team.

- Maintain over 150 servers, test machines, and virtual machines, providing installation, updates, troubleshooting and permissions.
- Create driver and application repository so our custom built unattended setup process could deploy OS installation with automatic driver detection by machine type.
- Utilize in-house tools and scripts to automate machine configuration.
- Investigate lab infrastructure issues of system hardware, power capacity, cooling capacity and network.
- Monitor and analyze workflow data, investigating workflow failures and hold machines in repro state to assist developer and test team.
- Configure KVM, KVM over IP, APC strips with LAN management and remote access permissions for developer and test team.

Software Test Engineer II

Microsoft via Compucom - Redmond, WA - February 2005 to February 2006

Software Test Engineer II on the Avalon team.

- Perform Enterprise level BVT (eBVT) for the Avalon UI on Windows Vista.
- Responsible for daily Build Verification Testing.
- Resolve asserts, test failures and analyze kernel debug breaks.
- Triage failures, create and assign bugs to appropriate owners using in-house reporting tool.
- Work with builders and developers to integrate fixes into the build.
- Utilize DFS to raise / lower build links.

Software Test Engineer

Microsoft via Manpower - Redmond, WA - February 2004 to November 2004

Software Test Engineer on the Media Player team.

- Test portable devices for Play4Sure logo program.
- Perform Windows Media Player 10 full manual test pass and daily BVT's.
- · Execute automated music service content testing.
- Document processes on team wiki.
- Report test results.
- Place in the top 5% in the "Audio/Video Test Team bug counts".

EDUCATION

Visual Communications

Art Institute of Seattle

Business Administration

Bellevue College

Computer Animation

Art Institute of Seattle

SKILLS

TESTING (10+ years), Device Driver (10+ years), TEST CASES (10+ years), USER INTERFACE (10+ years), Powershell (1 year), Javascript (Less than 1 year)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills

- Methods: Agile, Waterfall
- Desktop platforms: Windows 7, 8, 10, Mac OS X
- Mobile platforms: Android, Kindle, iOS
- Manual and Automated test experience: Application, device driver, cross-browser and mobile testing including functional, performance, load, regression, localization, user interface, compatibility, migration, sanity, compliance, usability, end-to-end
- Write test cases
- Test tools: WTT, Jira, TFS and WinDiff/Merge tools.
- Debugging: User, Kernel, Web
- Content Management Systems: Sitecore, Ektron CMS
- Coding Skills: PowerShell, JavaScript, XML, HTML